Preliminary Inventory to the Kostas Kouvaras Papers, 1944-1947
Hoover Institution Archives
Kostas Kouvaras Papers,
1944-1947
79006
Kouvaras, Kostas
1 manuscript box (0.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Reports and transcriptions of radio messages, relating to activities of the Greek resistance organization EAM-ELAS during World War II. Includes reports by German, Greek collaborationists, and EAM-ELAS officials, and a statement by K. Kouvaras relating to the origins of the Greek Civil War. Photocopy.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Biographical/Historical Note
First lieutenant, United States Army; head, Office of Strategic Services Pericles Mission to Greece, 1944-1945.
Access Points
Ethnikon Apeleutherotikon Metopon.; Hellenikos Laikos Apeleutherotikos Stratos.; United States. Office of Strategic Services.; Secret service--United States.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Collaborationists.; World War, 1939-1945--Greece.; World War, 1939-1945--Secret service.; World War, 1939-1945--Underground movements.; Greece.; Greece--History--Civil War, 1944-1949.; United States--Armed Forces.
Container List
- Report on Pericles Mission by Lt. (JG) Carl Devoe, United States Naval Reserve, Labor Desk, SI-0-0SS, 1944 August 25 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Field report by 1st. Lt. Costa G. Kouvaras (Pericles Mission), Labor Section, SI (Folder 2)
- German Situation Report, General Headquarters, 22nd XXII Mountain Army, 1944 July 8 (Folder 3)
- Pericles Mission mailed reports from inside Greece during occupation (Folder 4)
- Radio messages from Pericles Mission to the OSS office in Cairo (Folder 5)
- Radio messages from the Cairo office of the OSS to the Pericles Mission in the Greek mountains (Folder 6)
- Reports by Costa G. Kouvaras to the OSS Athens office, after the liberation of Greece (sorted by month to 1945 July) (Folder 7)
- Daily ELAS (Greek Guerrilla Army) reports of the military situation (Folder 8)
- EAM-ELAS reports on German atrocities (Folder 9)
- EAM-ELAS reports on the situation under occupation (Folder 10)
- Reports from the Greek Quisling government (Folder 11)
- EAM-ELAS appeals, 1944 December (Folder 12)
- Statement made by Costa G. Kouvaras before the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, 1947 March 31 (Folder 13)